Guide to the Brooklyn Historical Society institutional records ARC.288
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 11: Education, 1980-2020
  - Sub-series 11.2: Brooklyn Life Project, 1988-1990
    Sub-series 11.2: Brooklyn Life Project contains release forms, interview notes, and basic data forms. The basic data forms document the interviewee's name, address, age, birthplace, how they heard about the project, the neighborhoods they lived in, highlights of their Brooklyn experience, and comments from project staff.
    - Beveridge, Hortense, 1988 (Box 413, Folder 1)
    - Brooklyn Life Bulletin, 1990 (Box 413, Folder 2)
    - DiLorenzo, Marie, 1989 (Box 413, Folder 3)
    - Genovese, Jimmy, 1989 (Box 413, Folder 4)
    - Goldwag, Arnold, 1988 (Box 413, Folder 5)
    - Haran, Louise (Sunset Park), 1989 (Box 413, Folder 6)
    - Jenkins and Williams (Weeksville), 1988 (Box 413, Folder 7)
    - Kleban, Bernie, 1988 (Box 413, Folder 8)
    - Kolkin, Lucille, 1989 (Box 413, Folder 9)
    - Lutzky, Irwin, 1988 (Box 413, Folder 10)
    - Mcollough, Delores (Weeksville), 1988 (Box 413, Folder 11)
    - [Project Timeline], circa 1988 (Box 413, Folder 12)
    - Reich, Gertrude, 1988 (Box 413, Folder 13)
    - Russell, Carlos [Interview Transcript], circa 1989 (Box 413, Folder 14)
    - Sahadi, Charles, circa 1988 (Box 413, Folder 15)
    - Walsh, Tom, 1988 (Box 413, Folder 16)
    - Welch, Elizabeth (Weeksville), 1988 (Box 413, Folder 17)
  - Sub-series 11.3: Curriculum guides, kits, and lesson plans, 1985-2020
    Existence and Location of Copies
    As of April 2024, digital versions of the published guides are available on the Center for Brooklyn History website.
    Sub-series 11.3 contains curricula, teacher's guides, lesson plans, and kits developed by the educators at the Brooklyn Historical Society for both museum and classroom instruction. Many of the early curricula focus on Brooklyn Historical Society exhibitions, while later materials cover a range of historical topics, including the development of penicillin, enslavement and abolition, the history of sports, Dutch Brooklyn, and more. The kits include laminated images from the BHS collection and a teacher's guide with detailed lesson plans, historical overviews, and connections to learning standards.
    - At Home in Brooklyn [Teacher's Guide], 1985 (Box 414, Folder 1)
    - "New World Encounters: Jasper Danckaerts' View of Indian Life in 17th-Century Brooklyn" [Teacher's Guide], 1986 (Box 414, Folder 2)
    - Brooklyn Baseball and the Dodgers [Teacher's Guide], 1986 (Box 414, Folder 3)
    - Voices of the Civil Rights Movement in Brooklyn, 1989 (Box 414, Folder 4)
    - Many Faces, Many Ways [Lesson Plan Development], 1985-1990 (Box 414, Folder 5)
    - Many Faces, Many Ways [Object List], 1990 (Box 414, Folder 6-7)
      Contains descriptions and polaroids of objects utilized in 'Many Faces, Many Ways' school programs.
    - Many Faces, Many Ways [Slide Script], circa 1990 (Box 414, Folder 8)
    - Many Faces, Many Ways [Teacher's Guide], 1990 (Box 414, Folder 9)
    - Yellow Magic: The Story of Penicillin [Teacher's Guide], 1992 (Box 415, Folder 1)
    - Then and Now: At Home in Brooklyn [Curriculum Development], 1992-1995 (Box 415, Folder 2-3)
    - Then and Now: At Home in Brooklyn [Discussion Questions], circa 1992 (Box 415, Folder 4)
    - Then and Now: At Home in Brooklyn [Lesson Plan], 1992 (Box 415, Folder 5)
    - Crown Heights History Project [Teacher's Guide], 1995 (Box 415, Folder 6)
    - [Sunset Park Educational Package], 1997 (Box 415, Folder 7)
    - In Pursuit of Freedom: African Americans in Brooklyn and the Emancipation Proclamation, 1998 (Box 415, Folder 8)
    - Celebrating in Brooklyn Lesson Plan, 1999 (Box 415, Folder 9)
    - Brooklyn 2000 Time Capsule Curriculum (Box 415, Folder 10)
    - Brooklyn at Play Curriculum, circa 2000 (Box 415, Folder 11)
    - Pierrepont Papers [Curriculum Guide], 2000 (Box 416, Folder 1-2)
    - Stories in Stone: A Look at Brooklyn's History Through the Built Environment, 2000 (Box 416, Folder 3)
    - Picture This! Past to Present: Brooklyn at Work [Kit], 2002 (Box 740)
    - Picture This! Brooklyn Bridge [Kit], 2004 (Box 740)
    - Picture This! The Brooklyn Bridge [Supplementary Materials], 2004 (Box 416, Folder 4-7)
    - History Hunters [Kit], 2004 (Box 741)
    - History Hunters [Kit], 2004 (Box 742)
    - Gateway to the City: Teacher-Created Lessons Connecting New York City History to National Themes, 2004 (Box 417, Folder 1)
    - A Kid's Guide to Baseball in Brooklyn, 2005 (Box 417, Folder 2)
    - Picture This! Past to Present: Brooklyn on the Move [Kit], circa 2005-2006 (Box 740)
    - Slavery in New York: Brooklyn Stories, 2006-2007 (Box 417, Folder 3)
      Contains 1 DVD and 1 CD.
    - Brooklyn Navy Yard: Past, Present, and Future [Kit], 2011 (Box 740)
    - Exploring Pre-Revolutionary New York: The Ratzer Map, 2012 (Box 417, Folder 4)
    - In Pursuit of Freedom [Abolitionist Biographies], circa 2012 (Box 417, Folder 5)
    - In Pursuit of Freedom [Teacher's Manual], circa 2012 (Box 417, Folder 6)
    - Bats, Balls, Nets & Hoops: Stories of Sports in Brooklyn [Teacher's Guide], circa 2013 (Box 417, Folder 7)
    - Bats, Balls, Nets & Hoops [Demo Kit], circa 2013 (Box 417, Folder 8-10)
    - The Civil War: Voices from Brooklyn, circa 2015 (Box 418, Folder 1-2)
    - Dutch Breukelen: Where Brooklyn Began, 2015 (Box 418, Folder 3-4)
    - Voices of Mixed Heritage: Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations, 2015 (Box 418, Folder 5-6)
    - The U.S. Census: 1880-2020 [Teacher's Guide], circa 2015 (Box 418, Folder 7)
    - Freedom for One, Freedom for All? Abolition and Woman Suffrage, 1830s -1920s, 2016 (Box 419, Folder 1-2)
    - Created Equal: Image, Sound, Story [Student Journals], 2018 (Box 419, Folder 3-4)
    - Created Equal: Image, Sound, and Story [Teacher's Guide], 2018 (Box 419, Folder 5)
    - Mapping Freedom and Enslavement [Lesson Plan], 2018 (Box 419, Folder 6)
    - Mapping Freedom and Enslavement [Primary Sources], 2018 (Box 419, Folder 7)
    - Library / Archives Lesson Plan, 2019 (Box 419, Folder 8)
    - Our Communities (Lenape Focus) Lesson Plan, circa 2019 (Box 419, Folder 9)
    - Muslims in Brooklyn [Teacher Tool Box], 2020 (Box 419, Folder 10)
  - Sub-series 11.4: Public programming, 1984-2020
    From its establishment in 1984 until 2013, the Education Department was responsible for all public programming at the Brooklyn Historical Society. This included walking tours, lectures, panel discussions, workshops, and multicultural programs, such as cultural performances, children's activities, crafts, slide presentations, and parties. While the topics of these programs varied, they were typically linked to the ongoing exhibitions.
    In 2013, Marcia Ely was hired as Vice President of Programs and External Affairs, leading to the creation of a separate public programming department. As a result, the Education Department shifted its focus to school programming and teacher professional development workshops.
    Additional material on the Society's public programming can be found in Sub-series 12.3: Long Island Historical Society Programs and Sub-series 12.4: Brooklyn Historical Society Programs.
    Sub-series 11.4: Public Programming Files includes correspondence, invoices, promotional materials, press coverage, and program logs. The program logs document event logistics, attendance, income, successes, failures, and areas for improvement. Additionally, this sub-series contains walking tours, exhibition tours, and documentation related to teacher workshops offered by the Brooklyn Historical Society.
    - Black History Lectures, 1984 (Box 420, Folder 1)
    - Lectures, 1984 (Box 420, Folder 2)
    - Free for Fall Programs, 1984 (Box 420, Folder 3)
    - Dutch Homesteads Lectures, 1984-1985 (Box 420, Folder 4)
    - At Home in Brooklyn Lectures, 1984-1985 (Box 420, Folder 5)
    - Lectures / Walking Tours, 1985 (Box 420, Folder 6)
    - Noon Programs in Downtown Brooklyn [Brochures], 1985 (Box 420, Folder 7)
    - Prospect Park Lectures, 1985 (Box 420, Folder 8)
    - Walking Tours, 1985 (Box 420, Folder 9)
    - Black Women of Brooklyn Lectures, 1985-1986 (Box 420, Folder 10)
    - Indian Crafts Project, 1985-1986 (Box 420, Folder 11)
    - Borough Hall [School Program], circa 1986 (Box 420, Folder 12)
    - Fall Tours, 1986 (Box 421, Folder 1)
    - Brooklyn Neighborhoods [Lectures], 1987 (Box 421, Folder 2)
    - Walking Tour, Justin and John, 1986-1988 (Box 421, Folder 3)
    - Family Programs [Flyer], circa 1988 (Box 421, Folder 4)
    - Student Research Classes [Library Program Outline], 1988 (Box 421, Folder 5)
    - Downtown Brooklyn Walking Tours [Booklet], 1989 (Box 421, Folder 6)
    - Folk Arts and Traditional Storytelling Series [Brochure], 1989 (Box 421, Folder 7)
    - [Lecture Flyers], circa 1989 (Box 421, Folder 8)
    - Many Faces, Many Ways Programs, 1989 (Box 421, Folder 9)
    - Dutch Homesteads Bus Tour, 1984-1985, 1990-1991 (Box 421, Folder 10)
    - [Press Releases], 1989-1991 (Box 421, Folder 11)
    - Walt Whitman Series Calendar, 1992 (Box 421, Folder 12)
    - Musica Against Drugs [Unexecuted Workshop], 1992-1993 (Box 421, Folder 13)
    - Home in Sunset Park, 1993 (Box 421, Folder 14)
    - Brooklyn's Downtown Waterfront [Walking Tour], 1993 (Box 421, Folder 15)
    - Puppets with a Message about AIDS, 1993 (Box 421, Folder 16)
    - Downtown Brooklyn 101 [Walking Tour], 1993 (Box 421, Folder 17)
    - Williamsburgh Walking Tour, Artists Spaces, 1993 (Box 421, Folder 18)
    - Now That You Know: Disclosure and HIV [Panel Discussion], 1993 (Box 421, Folder 19)
    - Victorian Flatbush [Walking Tour], 1993 (Box 421, Folder 20)
    - Facing A Crisis with Humor, David Feinberg Reading, 1993 (Box 421, Folder 21)
    - 40th Anniversary of 1953 World Series, 1993 (Box 421, Folder 22)
    - Halloween Groups, 1993 (Box 421, Folder 23)
    - Halloween Haunted House, 1993 (Box 422, Folder 1)
    - Festival of Brooklyn Memories [Reading and Reminiscence], 1993 (Box 422, Folder 2)
    - Caribbean Delicacies on Nostrand Ave [Walking Tour], 1993 (Box 422, Folder 3)
    - Video Conversations: AIDS and Activism, 1993 (Box 422, Folder 4)
    - Living with and Writing about AIDS [Talk], 1993 (Box 422, Folder 5)
    - Only at BHS: Uncovering the Story of Your Home [Workshop], 1993 (Box 422, Folder 6)
    - Immigrant Theatre Project, 1993 (Box 422, Folder 7)
    - Kids Club, 1994 (Box 422, Folder 8)
    - Program Ideas, 1994 (Box 422, Folder 9)
    - Program Planning, 1994 September-December (Box 422, Folder 10)
    - Public Programs Budget, 1994 (Box 422, Folder 11)
    - Spires and Brownstones -- Architecture Lecture Series [Flyer], circa 1994 (Box 422, Folder 12)
    - Williamsburgh Savings Bank [Walking Tour], 1993-1994 (Box 422, Folder 13)
    - Volunteering and the AIDS Crisis [Panel Discussion], 1994 (Box 422, Folder 14)
    - Chinese New Year Program, 1994 (Box 422, Folder 15)
    - Elder Craftsmen -- African-American Quiltmaking [Workshop], 1993-1994 (Box 422, Folder 16)
    - African Doll Making [Workshop], 1994 (Box 422, Folder 17)
    - Rap it Up! [Workshop], 1993-1994 (Box 422, Folder 18)
    - Matzah Factory Tour, 1994 (Box 422, Folder 19)
    - Lunchtime Lecture: Ethnic Delights, 1994 (Box 422, Folder 20)
    - Illusion Productions, Dancing for Life [Performance], 1994 (Box 422, Folder 21)
    - Long-Term AIDS Survivors Panel, 1994 (Box 422, Folder 22)
    - Family Legends Into Theater [Drama Workshop], 1994 (Box 422, Folder 23)
    - Lunctime Lecture: Dining Out in Brooklyn, 1994 (Box 422, Folder 24)
    - Lubavitch Crown Heights [Walking Tour], 1994 (Box 422, Folder 25)
    - The Heyday of Brooklyn Theater [Lecture], 1994 (Box 422, Folder 26)
    - Crown Heights Walking Tour, 1994 (Box 422, Folder 27)
    - Crown Heights: We Call It Home [Panel Discussion], 1994 (Box 422, Folder 28)
    - Red Hook Walking Tour, 1994 (Box 422, Folder 29)
    - Musical Traditions of Crown Heights, 1993-1994 (Box 422, Folder 30)
    - Gospel Music and Beyond [Performance], 1994 (Box 423, Folder 1)
    - The Poetry of Urban Life [Reading and Open House], 1994 (Box 423, Folder 2)
    - Trades and Tradition [Video Presentation], 1994 (Box 423, Folder 3)
    - An Evening of West Indian Steel Drum Music [Performance], 1994 (Box 423, Folder 4)
    - Caribbean-American Crown Heights [Walking Tour], 1994 (Box 423, Folder 5)
    - Media Coverage of Crown Heights [Panel Discussion], 1994 (Box 423, Folder 6)
    - Hasidic and Klezmer Music [Performance], 1994 (Box 423, Folder 7)
    - Preserving Your Family's Photos [Workshop], 1994 (Box 423, Folder 8)
    - Park Slope Walking Tour, 1994 (Box 423, Folder 9)
    - A Kid's Tour of Crown Heights [Walking Tour], 1994 (Box 423, Folder 10)
    - Coney Island Memory Walk, 1994 (Box 423, Folder 11)
    - How Brooklyn Played [Lunchtime Lecture], 1994 (Box 423, Folder 12)
    - Park Slope: North and South [Walking Tour], 1994 (Box 423, Folder 13)
    - Green-Wood Walking Tour, 1994 (Box 423, Folder 14)
    - The World of the Revolutionary Soldier, 1994 (Box 423, Folder 15)
    - Oral History Basics, 1994 (Box 423, Folder 16)
    - Weeksville [Lunchtime Lecture], 1994 (Box 423, Folder 17)
    - Voices from the Lubavitch Community [Panel Discussion], 1993-1994 (Box 423, Folder 18)
    - Mexican Mask-Making [Workshop], 1994 (Box 423, Folder 19)
    - Remembering the Dodgers Sym-Phony [Talk / Reminiscence], 1994 (Box 423, Folder 20)
    - Beading Basics [Workshop], 1994 (Box 423, Folder 21)
    - From Man to Myth [Lecture], 1994 (Box 423, Folder 22)
    - Firefighting as a Window into the 19th Century [Lecture], 1994 (Box 423, Folder 23)
    - Jumping at the Sun [Storytelling], 1994 (Box 423, Folder 24)
    - Immigrant Experience Theater Project, 1994 (Box 423, Folder 25)
    - Frescura Antigua: Music of the Andes [Performance], 1994 (Box 423, Folder 26)
    - After-School / Summer Programs [Brochure], 1994-1995 (Box 423, Folder 27)
    - Fall Program Ideas, 1995 (Box 423, Folder 28)
    - Gallery Tour for Adult Groups, 1995 (Box 423, Folder 29)
    - Kids Day [Brochure], 1995 (Box 423, Folder 30)
    - Program Ideas, 1995 (Box 423, Folder 31)
    - Program Planning, 1995 January-April (Box 423, Folder 32)
    - Stories for a Summer Afternoon [Flyer], 1995 (Box 423, Folder 33)
    - Firehouse Architecture [Lecture], 1994-1995 (Box 423, Folder 34)
    - Inside the Fire Department [Tour], 1994-1995 (Box 423, Folder 35)
    - Sunset Park Walking Tour, 1994-1995 (Box 424, Folder 1)
    - Vacation Week Programs, 1994-1995 (Box 424, Folder 2)
    - Hair Locking Traditions [Workshop], 1994-1995 (Box 424, Folder 3)
    - Women Firefighters in NYC [Panel Discussion], 1994-1995 (Box 424, Folder 4)
    - Irish Genealogy [Lunctime Lecture], 1994-1995 (Box 424, Folder 5)
    - Lesbian Herstory Archives Tour, 1994-1995 (Box 424, Folder 6)
    - Fire Laddies and the Spaces of Urban Culture [Lecture], 1994-1995 (Box 424, Folder 7)
    - Irish Women's Music [Performance], 1994-1995 (Box 424, Folder 8)
    - Fire Houses and Halls [Slide Lecture], 1993-1995 (Box 424, Folder 9)
    - Fraktur Painting Workshop, 1994-1995 (Box 424, Folder 10)
    - The Rappin' Fireman [Performance], 1994-1995 (Box 424, Folder 11)
    - Future Developments [Lunchtime Lecture], 1995 (Box 424, Folder 12)
    - Saving the People's Firehouse [Video Screening], 1994-1995 (Box 424, Folder 13)
    - Hasidic Williamsburg [Walking Tour], 1995 (Box 424, Folder 14)
    - Lunctime Lecture: Stories of Downtown Brooklyn, 1995 (Box 424, Folder 15)
    - Sunset Park Walking Tour, 1995 (Box 424, Folder 16)
    - Laura Wetzler Concert, 1995 (Box 424, Folder 17)
    - Honeymooners Program, 1995 (Box 424, Folder 18)
    - Bike Tour of Brooklyn, 1995 (Box 424, Folder 19)
    - Kids Day, 1994-1995 (Box 424, Folder 20)
    - Urban Reporters [Panel Discussion], 1995 (Box 424, Folder 21)
    - Bay Ridge Walking Tour, 1995 (Box 424, Folder 22)
    - Preserving Your Family Photographs [Workshop], 1995 (Box 424, Folder 23)
    - Coney Island Walking Tour, 1995 (Box 424, Folder 24)
    - Memories of a Trolley Dodger [Lunchtime Lecture], 1995 (Box 424, Folder 25)
    - Festivals and Feathers [Workshop], 1995 (Box 424, Folder 26)
    - Caribbean Nostrand Avenue [Walking Tour], 1995 (Box 424, Folder 27)
    - Oral History Basics [Workshop], 1995 (Box 424, Folder 28)
    - Melanie Hope Greenberg [Meet the Author], 1995 (Box 424, Folder 29)
    - Bums No More [Lunchtime Lecture], 1995 (Box 424, Folder 30)
    - Borough Park Walking Tour, 1995 (Box 425, Folder 1)
    - Dodger Family Festival, 1995 (Box 425, Folder 2)
    - Brooklyn, Borough of Writers [Lunchtime Lecture], 1995 (Box 425, Folder 3)
    - Prime Time Brooklyn [Lecture], 1995 (Box 425, Folder 4)
    - Greenpoint Walking Tour, 1995 (Box 425, Folder 5)
    - From Family Stores Into Theatre [Workshop], 1995 (Box 425, Folder 6)
    - Family Quiltmaking [Workshop], 1995-1996 (Box 425, Folder 7)
    - Williamsburg Walking Tour, 1995 (Box 425, Folder 8)
    - February Fun Information, 1996 (Box 425, Folder 9)
    - Greetings from Brooklyn, circa 1996 (Box 425, Folder 10)
    - Spring Program Ideas, 1995-1996 (Box 425, Folder 11)
    - Sunday Programs, 1995-1996 (Box 425, Folder 12)
    - Where Brooklyn Worked [Lecture], 1996 (Box 425, Folder 13)
    - Brooklyn Underground Walking Tour, 1995-1996 (Box 425, Folder 14)
    - Sports, Race, and Heroes [Panel Discussion], 1995-1996 (Box 425, Folder 15)
    - February Fun Storytelling [Workshop], 1995-1996 (Box 425, Folder 16-18)
    - Hair Locking Traditions [Workshop], 1995-1996 (Box 425, Folder 19)
    - From Shore to Shore [Screening], 1995-1996 (Box 425, Folder 20)
    - Researching Your African American Heritage [Workshop], 1995-1996 (Box 425, Folder 21)
    - Changing Communities [Lecture], 1995-1996 (Box 425, Folder 22)
    - Smithsonian Speakers, 1996 (Box 425, Folder 23)
    - Summer Programs [Brochure], 1996 (Box 425, Folder 24)
    - Jewish Histories, Jewish Stories [Reading / Discussion], 1996 (Box 425, Folder 25)
    - Fathers and Daughters, Fathers and Sons [Poetry Reading], 1996 (Box 425, Folder 26)
    - Brooklyn, Reel to Reel [Film Screening], 1996 (Box 425, Folder 27)
    - Red Hook Walking Tour, 1996 (Box 425, Folder 28)
    - Brooklyn Kids Day, 1996 (Box 425, Folder 29)
    - Boerum Hill Walking Tour, 1996 (Box 425, Folder 30)
    - Sunset Park Opening, 1996 (Box 425, Folder 31)
    - Cobble Hill Walking Tour, 1996 (Box 425, Folder 32)
    - Young Voices: Growing Up Asian American, 1996 (Box 425, Folder 33)
    - Festivals and Folktales [Storytelling], 1996 (Box 425, Folder 34)
    - Lunchtime Lecture, 1996 (Box 425, Folder 35)
    - Carroll Gardens Walking Tour, 1996 (Box 425, Folder 36)
    - Publication Party, 1996 (Box 425, Folder 37)
    - What Makes Brooklyn…Brooklyn? [Lunchtime Lecture], 1996 (Box 425, Folder 38)
    - Crossing Borders [Poetry Reading], 1996 (Box 425, Folder 39)
    - Teacher Open House, 1996 (Box 426, Folder 1)
    - Prospect Park West [Walking Tour], 1996 (Box 426, Folder 2)
    - October Moon Festival, 1996 (Box 426, Folder 3)
    - Autumn Moon Festival, 1996 (Box 426, Folder 4-7)
    - Sunset Park Walking Tour, 1996 (Box 426, Folder 8)
    - New Neighbors: Old Traditions [Teacher Training Workshop], 1996 (Box 426, Folder 9)
    - Ditmas Park Walking Tour, 1996 (Box 426, Folder 10)
    - Brooklyn in Film, Books, and Art [Sunday Program], 1996 (Box 426, Folder 11)
    - How 'Bat Dai Do' Came to Be [Lunchtime Lecture], 1996 (Box 426, Folder 12)
    - Community Conversations, 1996 (Box 426, Folder 13)
    - Family Photo Archive Workshop, 1996 (Box 426, Folder 14)
    - Lunchtime Lecture: New York Before Chinatown, 1996 (Box 426, Folder 15)
    - MCA Highschool Presentation, 1996 (Box 426, Folder 16)
    - Bat Dai Do Programs, 1996-1997 (Box 426, Folder 17)
    - Exploring Cultures Teacher Workshop, 1997 (Box 426, Folder 18)
    - HIV / AIDS Education Programs, 1997 (Box 426, Folder 19)
    - Staff Development Workshop, 1997 (Box 426, Folder 20)
    - Summer Programs, 1997 (Box 426, Folder 21)
    - Walking Tours [Flyer], 1997 (Box 426, Folder 22)
    - Williamsburg Walking Tour, 1997 (Box 426, Folder 23)
    - Jackie Robinson Day at Borough Hall, 1997 (Box 426, Folder 24)
    - Kids Day, 1997 (Box 426, Folder 25)
    - Jackie Robinson Days, 1997 (Box 426, Folder 26)
    - Sheepshead Bay Walking Tour, 1997 (Box 426, Folder 27)
    - Exhibit Opening, In Pursuit of Freedom at City Hall, 1997 (Box 426, Folder 28)
    - Emancipation Proclamation Exhibit at Borough Hall, 1997-1998 (Box 426, Folder 29)
    - History Talks Research, 1994-1998 (Box 427, Folder 1-5)
      Includes oral history transcripts from the West Indian Carnival Documentation project.
    - History Talks [Program Outline], 1998 (Box 427, Folder 6)
    - Historic Brooklyn Fire Tour, 1997-1998 (Box 427, Folder 7)
    - BAM Event, 1998 (Box 427, Folder 8)
    - In Pursuit of Freedom Workshop, circa 1998 (Box 427, Folder 9)
    - Brooklyn Talks, 1999 (Box 427, Folder 10)
    - Juneteenth Celebration, 1999 (Box 427, Folder 11)
    - Lott House, 1999-2000 (Box 428, Folder 1)
    - [Workshop Flyers], 1999-2000 (Box 428, Folder 2)
    - Brooklyn Cultural Adventures Program [Brochure], 2000 (Box 428, Folder 3)
    - Waterfront Boat Tours, 2000 (Box 428, Folder 4)
    - Brooklyn Heights Walking Tour, circa 2000 (Box 428, Folder 5)
    - Neighborhood Walking Tours, circa 2000 (Box 428, Folder 6)
    - Battle of Brooklyn, 2001 (Box 428, Folder 7)
    - Horsing Around in Prospect Park [Postcard], 2002 (Box 428, Folder 8)
    - Brooklyn Works Docent Guide, circa 2003 (Box 428, Folder 9)
    - Neighborhood Walking Tour Cards, circa 2003 (Box 428, Folder 10)
    - Getting to Know Greenpoint [Walking Tour], circa 2004 (Box 428, Folder 11)
    - Meet Brooklyn Authors, 2004 (Box 428, Folder 12)
    - Worklore Labor Panels, 2004 (Box 428, Folder 13)
    - [Event Postcards], 2003-2006 (Box 428, Folder 14)
    - Caribbean American Heritage Month, 2006 (Box 428, Folder 15)
    - Open House NY Weekend, 2007 (Box 428, Folder 16)
    - [Event Flyers], 2007 (Box 428, Folder 17)
    - Gravesend Walking Tour, 2009 (Box 428, Folder 18)
    - Brooklyn Navy Yard Public Tours, circa 2012 (Box 428, Folder 19)
    - IPOF Exhibit Tours, 2013 (Box 428, Folder 20)
    - BHS Building Tour, 2014 (Box 428, Folder 21)
    - NEH Summer Institute for School Teachers, 2015-2016 (Box 429, Folder 1)
    - Inventing Brooklyn Tour, circa 2017 (Box 429, Folder 2)
    - Tour Outlines, 2018 (Box 429, Folder 3)
    - Chancellor's Day Professional Development "Brooklyn Abolitionists", 2018 (Box 429, Folder 4)
    - LGBTQ Teacher Workshop, 2018 (Box 429, Folder 5)
    - DUMBO Self Guide, 2018-2019 (Box 429, Folder 6)
    - Chancellor's Day Professional Development "Muslims in Brooklyn", 2019 (Box 429, Folder 7)
    - Cool Culture [Family Program], 2019 (Box 429, Folder 8)
    - 400 Years of Inequality [Teacher Workshop], 2019 (Box 429, Folder 9)
    - [Election Day Professional Development, "Muslims in Brooklyn"], 2019 (Box 429, Folder 10)
    - History by Design [Teacher Workshop], 2019 (Box 429, Folder 11)
    - Civics for All [Teacher Workshop], 2020 (Box 429, Folder 12)
    - Shubert Arts Leadership Institute [Teacher Workshop], 2020 (Box 429, Folder 13)
    - Center for Arts Education [Workshops], 2020 (Box 429, Folder 14)
  - Sub-series 11.5: Photographs, 1987-2002, bulk 1999-2000
    Sub-series 11.5: Photographs contains prints, negatives, and slides that document various school and public programs conducted by the education department, as well as those used for instruction and promotional purposes.
    - BHS Staff, circa 1999 (Box 430, Folder 1)
    - [Boat Tour Photos], circa 2000 (Box 430, Folder 2)
    - Brooklyn Brewery Tour, circa 1999 (Box 430, Folder 3)